JOANA BRITO

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

Condon

+44 7753218292

joanabrito216@gmail.com

₩ Portfolio

គ្រៃ joana-brito

@joanaBrit

SKILLS

FRONTEND BACKEND

React

Node.js

JavaScript

MongoDB

Typescript

Express.js

• HTML

Python

• CSS

SOFT SKILLS

- · Problem Solving
- · Time Management
- Adaptability
- Communication
- · Attention to Detail

EXPERIENCES

VOLUNTEER

Women Coding Community

2024 - Present

- Helping on the organization of mentorship programme.
- · General volunteer.

FREELANCE FASHION ASSISTANT, HARRIET NICOLSON

2022 - 2023

 Plan and manage photoshoots, create social media content.

VISUAL MERCHANDISER, ZARA

2020 - 2022

 Researched fashion trends and developed retail store strategies to increase sales, including store layouts, inclusive styled mannequins.

PROFILE

I'm a recent General Assembly Software Engineering Graduate, available as a junior engineer across the full stack. I'm particularly interested in web development, where I can combine my previous background in design and fashion, with my new technical skills built through an intensive bootcamp. I'm currently improving my skills through additional personal projects, where I am learning Typescript and gaining more experience with React and Material UI.

PROJECTS

Tube Wise

- · A journey planning web app integrating TfL APIs for service statuses.
- Emphasized the importance of writing maintainable code and thoroughly reading API documentation.
- · React, Typescript, Material UI, Node.js.

Famous Wardrobe

- A fashion app focusing on User experience and celebrity-inspired outfits.
- Gained understanding of relational databases and Python, saw the importance of having a structured plan and break down a problem.
- · React, Sass, Bootstrap, Python, Django, PostgreSQL.

SEI Quiz App

- Full-stack app for quiz enthusiasts covering software engineering topics.
- User-centric design importance. Emphasized the importance of seeking help when needed and effective communication within the team.
- React, Sass, Bootstrap, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB.

Disney Characters

- For users interested in learning about Disney's secondary characters.
- Learned the importance of collaborating within a team to succeed, importance of selecting the right API, and manipulating data.
- · React, JavaScript, CSS, Sass.

Turtle Bay

- A game based on Frogger, where a turtle navigates obstacles.
- Learned CSS tools and animations, effective time management and adaptability in handling unexpected challenges.
- JavaScript, HTML, CSS.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING BOOTCAMP

General Assembly, Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

- 4 solo and group projects to put technical learning into practice, and to develop team work, time management and problem solving skills.
- Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, SaaS, Bootstrap.
- Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Python, MongoDB, Django.

BA FASHION DESIGN

University of Lisbon, Politecnico Di Milano, 2014 - 2017